Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Tangos, 1983-1991
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Study scores, 1983-1991, V.; Box 5, Folder 233-242
  - Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Tango Boosey & Hawkes, Inc., 1977. Publisher no.: BH. BK. 765 (Box 5, Folder 241)
  - Weill, Kurt, 1900-1950. Sailors Tango from Happy End Universal Edition, 1980. Publisher no.: UE 17243 (Box 5, Folder 242)
- Performance materials, 1984-1987, VI.; Box 5, Folder 242-250
  These items pertain to Mikhashoff's performances of the tango collection; includes programs, reviews, handwritten lists of tangos received, and samples of the covers that were to be used for the proposed publication by Quadrivium Press
  - Preface to the Tango Collection written by Yvar Mikhashoff (Box 5, Folder 243)
  - Tango lecture handout (Box 5, Folder 244)
  - Lists (30) of tangos in collection, 1984-1987 (Box 5, Folder 245)
  - Lists (15) of tangos (undated) (Box 5, Folder 246)
  - Lists (3) of recorded tangos (undated) (Box 5, Folder 247)
  - Programs (10) of performances, 1984-1987 (Box 5, Folder 248)
  - Reviews (4) of Mikhashoff's performances, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - Samples of covers and postcards created for the tango collection. Design by Bud Jacobs (Box 5, Folder 250)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Tangos; Music--Manuscripts; Music--Manuscripts--Facsimiles; Piano music
Genres
Correspondence; Scores; Articles; Programs; Clippings
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Tangos in the Yvar Mikhashoff Archive: Publication Information
A list in five parts: tangos in the archive commissioned by Yvar Mikhashoff and Quadrivium Press (126 titles), commissioned tangos not in the archive (7 titles), tangos in the Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Annotated Scores (8 titles), tangos arranged by Yvar Mikhashoff (2 titles, not including his arrangement of John Cage's Perpetual Tango), and tangos composed by Mikhashoff (1 title and sketches for two works). The first section of the list includes information about the availability of the tangos.